Contact

+2 (012) 2763-3600 (Mobile) bftawfik@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bftawfik (LinkedIn) bftawfik.github.io (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Front-end Development
Web Development
Game Development

Languages

Arabic (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Adobe Flash Designer certified JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Git Essential Training Adobe Photoshop CS2 Web design (CIW) 401

Bishoy Tawfik

Frontend Developer (React Developer) at NasNav

Summary

I'm a 3+ years experienced front-end developer, with a background in programming since 2008.

Knocking every door with a goal of gaining knowledge and experience.

Hope to find my way to be the best developer I can be.

Seeking new challenges and opportunities to build myself.

I have two passions my family and the programming.

I'm trying always to find solutions through programming to any problem I had.

I hope to find the right place to reach my full potential.

Experience

NasNav

Frontend Developer (React Developer)
October 2019 - Present

Cairo Governorate, Egypt

Developing new user-facing features using React.js.

Building reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.

Translating designs and wire-frames into high quality code.

Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of webcapable devices and browsers.

Middle East Broadcasting Center

11 years 2 months

Front End Developer

July 2016 - July 2019 (3 years 1 month)

https://www.google.com.eg/maps/place/Egyptian+Media+Production+City++EMPC/@29.9

Creating Interactive Custom-Made web elements.

Creating Interactive Custom-Made games and applications.

Senior Action Script Developer February 2016 - June 2016 (5 months) https://www.google.com.eg/maps/place/Egyptian+Media+Production+City+-+EMPC/@29.9

Creating Interactive Custom-Made web elements.

Creating Interactive Custom-Made Flash games and applications.

Intermediate Action Script Developer

June 2008 - January 2016 (7 years 8 months)

https://www.google.com.eg/maps/place/Egyptian+Media+Production+City++EMPC/@29.9

Creating Interactive Custom-Made web elements.

Creating Interactive Custom-Made Flash games and applications.

Clip Solutions

Flash Developer

January 2008 - June 2008 (6 months)

Creating Interactive Custom-Made Presentations .

Creating Flash CDs With Interactive Games for Kids.

Creating Web Applications components

Russian Cultural Center

Freelance Graphics Instructor

May 2007 - January 2008 (9 months)

https://www.google.com.eg/maps/place/Russian+Cultural+Center/@30.0110896,31.2410

Courses Instructed:

RCC Graphics Professional Diploma & RCC Web Design Professional Diploma.

Including: [Adobe Photoshop CS2, Adobe Illustrator CS2, Adobe Indesign CS2, Macromedia Freehand MXa, Corel Draw, Quark Xpress, Macromedia Flash 8, Macromedia Dream Weaver 8, HTML and CSS].

Elshababia channel

Graphics & multimedia designer

November 2006 - February 2007 (4 months)

Design Programs Logos.

Design Programs Introduction.

YAT Learning Centers

Freelance Graphics & Web Design Instructor.

December 2005 - February 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Courses Instructed:

- -YAT Professional Training Program for Ministry of Communication and Information Technology (MCIT) Graphics & Diploma Including: [Adobe Photoshop CS2, Adobe Illustrator CS2, Adobe Indesign CS2, Design and Artwork Principles].
- -YPDW Diploma including: [Macromedia Flash 8 Basic, Macromedia Dream weaver 8, HTML and CSS].
- -Corel Draw & amp; Adobe After Effect.

YAT Learning Centers

Fulltime Graphics & Web Design Instructor. December 2005 - November 2006 (1 year)

Courses Instructed:

- YAT Professional Training Program for Ministry of Communication and Information Technology (MCIT) Graphics & Multimedia Design and Development 9 Month Track.
- 2. YPDG Diploma Including: [Adobe Photoshop CS2, Adobe Illustrator CS2, Adobe Indesign CS2, Design and Artwork Principles].
- 3. YPDW Diploma including: [Macromedia Flash 8 Basic, Macromedia Dream weaver 8, HTML and CSS].
- 4. Corel Draw & Adobe After Effect.

Time Advertising Agency

Graphic designer

January 2004 - September 2004 (9 months)

Printing and Advertising Designs.

Signs Designs.

Multimedia CD's.

AMG Advertising Agency

Graphic designer

July 2003 - December 2003 (6 months)

Designing for Light boxes.

Organizing for the printing Operation.

Instructor [private and volunteer work

Education

Information Technology Institute (ITI), (Information and Decision Support Center, the Egyptian Cabin

diploma, Multimedia · (2004 - 2005)

Egypt Graduation Project (EGP)

diploma, Web Design · (2002 - 2003)

Helwan University Cairo

Bachelor of Applied Arts, Printing Publishing & Packing · (1997 - 2002)